BERNARDO SANTANA

12850 W State Rd 84 lot 6-7 • Davie, FL 33325

C (954) 516-9673 • bernardo.santana.dev@gmail.com

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / MOBILE DEVELOPER

Performance Summary

Detail oriented Software Engineer, with 2 years of experience in development of native and web-based mobile apps. Strong background on Electronics Engineering (Bachelor's Degree), with affinity for hardware integration and manipulation of external devices. Keen problem solving skills combined with ability to learn and adapt to new technologies evidenced by the implementation of custom solutions in different platforms. Effective communicator that can interface with professionals at all levels in both English and Spanish.

Technical Skills

- Swift
- Objective C
- iOS / Apple TV / Watch kit
- Mobile App Development
- Android

- OOP
- Dynamic Programming
- Hardware/Electronics
- Control Theory
- TCP/IP, LAN/WAN

- Python
- Django
- RethinkDB
- PostgreSQL
- Multithreading

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Bundle UK 2015 - present

Software Engineer / Lead Developer

In charge of development and maintenance of the iOS app since the concept phase, as well as the Real-time commenting service for it (python-Tornado). Supervise and coordinate a startup team of 5 in all areas of engineering of the platform: CMS, Machine Learning disambiguation, Design and Mobile App.

- Develop and maintain the codebase for the native iOS App in Swift, according to the design guidelines and meeting the highest standards of quality.
- Iterate and improve the app with Multithreading Techniques (GCD), sleek animations (Core Animation), efficient storage (Core Data) and external libraries for networking (Alamofire) and authentication (Facebook API).
- Develop and maintain a commenting server based in Python-Tornado server with a database on rethinkDB to enable Real-Time features in the app.
- Establish weekly and monthly goals for each of the members of the team, based on a continuous delivery philosophy.
- Setup features and releases according to the company's goals and milestones.
- Keep track of development and redistribute time resources when necessary.

Artonics International 2015 - present

Mobile Developer

Redesign and refurbish the drawing engine for the mobile app **Nebula** (in the App Store).

- Translate and update the deprecated codebase (2010) from Objective-C to Swift
- Redesign drawing methods to optimize speed and responsiveness to leverage Real-time feedback drawing.
- Engineer custom solutions and create new features.

Mobile Media Networks 2014 – 2015

Software Developer

Developed Mobile Apps for Android, iOS and web based (Phonegapp/Cordova) platforms. Gained valuable experience modifying, fixing, adding features and creating numerous apps.

Projects:

- Played an active role in the new-product development from concept through launch phase for **Dualvis.io**, a
 multi-platform general TV experience enhancer app for iOS. Runner-up startup project in Startup-Chile
 contest. Mocked-up, developed and tested the complete interface.
- Updated and maintained the code base for **Meridiano Extra** in both Android and iOS. Increased responsiveness, added other sport features, fixed serious memory leaks and refreshed the interface.
- Gained mobile development skills by fixing bugs, adding new features and running tests in the following apps:
 - My Renault (Colombia), Diario La República (Colombia), Chevrolet (Colombia)

General Electric 2013 - 2014

Intern

Designed and documented an Auxiliary Fluid Handling System for a Central Processing Facility in the Orinoco Oil Belt. Gained extensive experience in GE-IP control software for industrial equipment, utilizing GE-Proficy and Fanuc products. Feasibility research and analysis of new business opportunities for GE in Venezuela, specifically in the Orinoco Heavy Oil Belt. Technical/Commercial presentations for diverse product lines.

• Academic thesis: Automation System proposal for a Central Processing Facilities in the Orinoco Oil Belt

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

BS, Electronics Engineering. Cum Laude

SIMON BOLIVAR UNIVERSITY, VENEZUELA

Projects:

- Acquisition and Signal Processing System (Hardware) for cardiac signals
- Design and Construction of a musical instrument based in Sensors and Actuators. Signal acquisition in LabView through TCP/IP protocols,
- Design and Construction of an automated mobile robotic system. Image acquisition and recognition made in Processing (open source), hardware controls made with Arduino UNO board.

Selected Courses: Robotics - Control Theory - Signals & Systems - Electronic Devices - Solid State Electronics - Mobile Communications, Optical Communications - Telecommunication Systems - Computer Architecture - Programming

Robotics / Telecommunications Semester

CZECH TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY AT PRAGUE, CZECH REPUBLIC

Professional Development

Participation in numerous Hackathons:

- HackSoton iOS App/Arduino Ethernet shield interface for house actuators model
- HackRisk Safely share medical records + Watch OS (Also used NEST API)
- HackSummit BizSpark experiment
- Capital Factory Apple TV Simple apple TV game

Participation in Capital Factory Accelerator at Austin, TX

Member of AIESEC - Exchange participant in England.

Certification CCNA Level 1 (Cisco)

Machine Learning MOOC (Coursera)